plano.gov 2006-06-15

# The City of Plano, Texas Official Website

**Privacy Statement    **        

This policy describe the city of Plano, Texas privacy practices regarding information collected from and provided to visitors to the site, www.planotx.org and all departmental sites contained within. It contains information about specific data collected and how that information is used. This privacy statement applies to this web site and all websites of the city of Plano. When you follow a link to another site, even the sites of other governmental agencies, this policy will not apply. You should check the privacy policy of each of these sites if you have concerns about how they handle personally identifiable information. This statement may be updated periodically; please check back from time to time.

**Collection and Use of Information**

The city of Plano does not sell or rent personally identifiable information. Please be aware that when you provide information to any government entity, however, that information may be subject to the Texas Public Information Act and applicable federal legislation. Information about the Texas Public Information Act is available from the Office of the Attorney General at:

The city of Plano may be legally required to provide personally identifiable information to the appropriate governmental authorities. The City of Plano will cooperate with law enforcement agencies in identifying those who use our services for illegal activities. We reserve the right to report to law enforcement agencies any activities deemed to be illegal.

**  
If You Send Us Personal Information**

If you choose to provide us with personal information - as in filling out a form, an online transaction and/or email - we use that information to process your request, complete a transaction, or respond to your message.

We do not collect personal information for any purpose other than to serve or respond to you. We only share information you give us with another governmental or business agency, if your inquiry/transaction relates to that agency or business, or as otherwise required by law.

Information Collected and Stored Automatically

**Privacy Statement**

This policy describe the city of Plano, Texas privacy practices regarding information collected from and provided to visitors to the site, www.planotx.org and all departmental sites contained within. It contains information about specific data collected and how that information is used. This privacy statement applies to this web site and all websites of the city of Plano. When you follow a link to another site, even the sites of other governmental agencies, this policy will not apply. You should check the privacy policy of each of these sites if you have concerns about how they handle personally identifiable information. This statement may be updated periodically; please check back from time to time.

**Collection and Use of Information**  
The city of Plano does not sell or rent personally identifiable information. Please be aware that when you provide information to any government entity, however, that information may be subject to the Texas Public Information Act and applicable federal legislation. Information about the Texas Public Information Act is available from the Office of the Attorney General at:

<http://www.oag.state.tx.us/opinopen/opengovt.htm>

The city of Plano may be legally required to provide personally identifiable information to the appropriate governmental authorities. The City of Plano will cooperate with law enforcement agencies in identifying those who use our services for illegal activities. We reserve the right to report to law enforcement agencies any activities deemed to be illegal.

**If You Send Us Personal Information**

If you choose to provide us with personal information - as in filling out a form, an online transaction and/or email - we use that information to process your request, complete a transaction, or respond to your message.

We do not collect personal information for any purpose other than to serve or respond to you. We only share information you give us with another governmental or business agency, if your inquiry/transaction relates to that agency or business, or as otherwise required by law.

**Information Collected and Stored Automatically**  

If you do nothing during your visit but browse through the website, read pages, or download information, we will gather and store certain information about your visit automatically. This information does not identify you personally. We automatically collect and store only the following information about your visit: 

  1. The type of browser and operating system used to access our site; 

  2. The date and time you access our site; 

  3. The pages your visit; and 

  4. If you linked to the city of Plano website from another website, the address of that website.

We use this information to help us make our site more useful to visitors - to learn about the number of visitors to our site and the types of technology our visitors use. We do not track or record information about individuals and their visits.

**Links to Non-City of Plano Sites**  
The city of Plano website and all its related departmental websites have links to many other governmental agencies and organizations, both public and private. Once you link to another non-city of Plano site, you are subject to the privacy policy of the new site. The City of Plano is not responsible for content carried on non-city of Plano sites to which we link.  

**E-Mail Request for Information**

We use links throughout our site to provide you with the opportunity to contact us by e-mail to ask questions, request information and materials, or provide comments and suggestions. You may also request the opportunity to have one of our employees contact you personally to provide additional information about our services. To do so, we may request additional personal information from you to help us satisfy your request. The information requested will not be rented or sold to outside firms for any purpose.

**E-Commerce Tracking of Online Transactions**  
For online government transactions conducted on this site, you will be asked to enter certain information about yourself. The specifics of this information will vary as required by the type of transaction. The information requested will include the same information that would be requested if you performed the identical transaction in person rather than online. Whenever personal information is requested from you on this site, there will be an indication of whether your disclosure of such information is mandatory or optional. Information collected in the course of the transaction is used for the purposes of conducting online transactions with the appropriate governmental entities (e.g., the payment of utility bills, the renewal of a license, permit or the like); to send you an email confirming your transaction; to forward new announcements or content features to you, only if you have chosen to request this service.

**Notification of Changes to this Privacy Statement**

If a material change is made to the Privacy Statement and/or the way we use personally identifiable information, we will prominently post the nature of such change on the first page of this Statement. In no even will any such change to this statement apply with respect to data previously collected through this site.
